American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIf. 1866-1886 APS.Archives.IIf APS.Archives.IIf
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Oct. 28, 1885; 5x6-1/2; Claypole, E. W. (Edward Waller), 1835-1901
    Akron, Ohio, A.L.S. 1p.,end. Enc.wanting. Acknowledges receipt of publication.
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Oct. 29, 1885; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p.,end., and add. Enc. wanting Asking for return of manuscript.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 30, 1885; 5x3; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    [Phila.,] A.L.on postal card S.with rubber stamp. 1p.and add. Approves action in re Cope.
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Oct. 30, 1885; 3x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Thanks for manuscript.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Nov. 1, 1885; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Etting, Frank M. (Frank Marx)
    Concordville, Pa., A.L.S. 3p.,end.,and end. Concerning the draft of the Declaration. Refers to Franklin,Jefferson and [J.] Adams. FILM 54-66 199 FRAME 191 709
  - Memorandum to the A.P.S., Nov. 2, 1885; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Vassar brothers institute, Poughkeepsie, N.Y.
    D.S.:C[harles] L[Awrence] Bristol,secretary 1p.,end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Nov. 2, 1885; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Harvard College Observatory
    Cambridge, L.S.:Edward C[harles] Pickering. 1p., end.,and end. Asking for publication. Mentions R.T. Paine and S.Borden.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 3, 1885; 10x8; United States. Army. Signal Corps
    Wash.,D.C., L.S.:W[illiam] B[abcock] Hazen. 1p.,end. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Nov. 3, 1885; 8x5; Mallet, John William
    University of Virginia, A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Returns his diploma of membership for correction.
  - Letter to general manager of Adams & co., Nov. 4, 1885; 12-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    Phila., A.Dr.of L.S.:H[enry] P[hillips], secretary. 1p.and end. Partly in short-hand. Concerning delivery of packages.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Nov. 4, 1885; 3x5; Harvard University. Museum of Comparative Zoology
    Cambridge, L.on postal card S.:A[lexander] Agassiz, in another hand. 1p.and add. Concerning sending of mail.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Nov. 4, 1885; 3x5; Lesley, J. P. (J. Peter), 1819-1903
    [Phila.], A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Concerning Jefferson and the draft of the Declaration. FILM 199 FRAME 710
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Nov. 4, 1885; 7x4-1/2; Cleemann, Thomas M.
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p.,end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Nov. 5, 1885; 6-1/2x5-1/2; M’Calla & Stavely
    [Phila.], L. 1p.and add.,end. Sorry for error.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Nov. 7, 1885; 5x3; Brooklyn Library
    Brooklyn, L.on postal card S.:Cha[rle]s A.Horn. 1p.and add.,end. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to Fred[erick] Fraley, Nov. 7, [1885]; 7x4-1/2; Mitchell, Silas Weir
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 2p.,end. Declines to prepare obituary of [G.] Harrison.
  - Letter to [Frederick] Fraley, Nov. 9, 1885; 9x5-1/2; Lesley, J. P. (J. Peter), 1819-1903
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Agrees to prepare obituary of [J.] Macfarlane.
  - Letter to Henry C.Phillips [Henry Phillips], Nov. 9, 1885; 8x5; Redfield, John Howard, 1815-1895
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerning the Michaux journal.
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Nov. 10, 1885; 6-1/2x5; Claypole, E. W. (Edward Waller), 1835-1901
    Akron, Ohio, A.L.S. 1p.,end. Enc.wanting. Thanks for favor.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Nov. 12, 1885; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Royal Observatory, Greenwich
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.:W.H.M.Christie 1p. Enc.wanting. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Nov. 13, 1885; 10-1/2x8; Canadian Institute (1849-1914)
    Toronto, A.L.S.:R.W.Young. 1p.,end.by H[enry] P[hillips]. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to H[enr]y Phillips, Nov. 13, 1885; 3-1/2x5-1/2; A. Dulau & Co.
    London, L.on postal card. 1p.and add.,end. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Nov. 14, 1885; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Harvard College Observatory
    Cambridge, L.S.:Edward C[harles] Pickering. 1p., end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Nov. 16, 1885; 8x5; Gray, Asa, 1810-1888
    Brookline, Mass., L.S.:Asa Gray and C[harles] S[prague] Sargeant. 3p.,end. Requesting permission to have copy made of the Michaux diary.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Nov. 17, 1885; 10x8; Royal Statistical Society (Great Britain)
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.:J[oseph] Whittall,librarian. 1p. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Nov. 17, 1885; 8x5; Royal Society of Victoria (Melbourne, Vic.)
    A.L.S.:H.R.Bentley. 1p.,end. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Nov. 17, 1885; 10x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Wash.,D.C., L.S.:Spencer F[ullerton] Baird,secretary. 1p.,end. No information on Louis Gruneir.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Nov. 19, 1885; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Returns paper.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 19, 1885; 10x8; United States. Army. Signal Corps
    Wash., D.C., L.S.:F.B.Jones. 1p.,end. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Nov. 20, 1885; 10-1/2x8; Canadian Institute (1849-1914)
    Toronto, A.L.S.:R.W.Young. 1p.,end.,and end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 22, 1885; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Lesley, J. P. (J. Peter), 1819-1903
    A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Sends memo-book manuscript of the Wistar association.
  - Letter to Hen[r]y Phillips, Nov. 22, 1885; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Lesley, J. P. (J. Peter), 1819-1903
    A.L.S. 1p. Declines chairmanship of committee. Mentions [P.] Frazer.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Nov. 22, 1885; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Lesley, J. P. (J. Peter), 1819-1903
    A.L.S. 1p.,end. Enc.wanting. Concerning obituary of [J.] Macfarlane.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Nov. 23, 1885; 8-1/2x5-1/2; France. Ministère de l'agriculture, du commerce et des travaux publics
    Paris, L.S.:[Charles] R[ené] Zeiller. 3p.,end. In French. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 25, 1885; 8x5; Capellini, Giovanni, 1833-1927
    Bologne, A.L.S. 3p. Suggests G.Meneghini for membership in Society.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Nov. 25, 1885; 7x4-1/2; Wagner, Samuel, 1842-
    A.L.S. 2p.,end. Offers publications to Society.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Nov. 25, 1885; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Concerning the appointment of [Wm.?] Sellers to conduct election of members.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Nov. 28, 1885; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. Enc.wanting. Additions to his paper. Refers to [P.] Frazer.
  - Letter to Prof. John P.Lesley[J.Peter Lesley], Nov. 29, 1885; 9x5-1/2; Peabody, Selim H. (Selim Hobart), 1829-1903
    Champaign, Ill., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Asking for publications.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Nov. 30, 1885; 8-1/2x5; Johns Hopkins University
    Baltimore, A.L.S.:N.Murray. 1p.,end. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Nov., 1885; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., Friday, A.L.S. 2p.,end. Concerning publication of his paper.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Dec. 1, 1885; 7x4-1/2; Wagner, Samuel, 1842-
    A.L.S. 2p.,end. Concerning donation of publications.
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S. [Henry Phillips], Dec. 2, 1885; 3x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    [Phila.], A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add.,end. Concerning the correction of his plate.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Dec. 3, 1885; 9x5-1/2; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p.and end. Enc.wanting. Suggesting change in his manuscript on the Laws and Regulations of the Society. Refers to [E.D.] Cope.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Dec. 4, 1885; 10-1/2x8; Canadian Institute (1849-1914)
    Toronto, A.L.S.:R.W.Young. 2p.,end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Dec. 4, 1885; 3x5; Macnamara, William
    Bridgeport, Conn., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Asking for information about Society.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Dec. 8, 1885; 10-1/2x8; Canadian Institute (1849-1914)
    Toronto, A.L.S.:R.W.Young. 2p.,end. Financial matter involving exchange of publications.
  - Letter to Secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Dec. 9, 1885; 3x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.on postal card S. 1p. and add.,end. Additions to his paper.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Dec. 9, 1885; 9x5-1/2; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Enc. Concerning changes in the Laws and Regulations of the Society. For enclosure, see APS, Report of Board of Officers and Council ....; [Dec.9, 1885]
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Dec. 9, 1885; 11x8; Société entomologique de Belgique
    Brussels, L.S.:Aug[uste] Lameere. 1p.,end. In French. Concerning exchange of publications.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Dec. 9, 1885; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    A.L.S. 1p. Asking for Treasurer's report.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Dec. 9, 1885; 5x3; Smith, Lloyd P. (Lloyd Pearsall), 1822-1886
    [Phila.], A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Asking for a Latin phrase.
  - Report of Board of Officers and Council ... on proposed changes in the laws and regulations of the society., December 9, 1885; American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Dec. 10, 1885; 8x5; U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey
    Phila., A.L.S.:Spencer C.McCorkle. 1p.,end.,and end. Enc.wanting. Sends report. Asking about publication.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 12, 1885; 10x8; United States. Army. Signal Corps
    Wash., D.C., T.L.S.:F.B.Jones. 1p.,end. Asking for express receipt.
  - Letter to Henry C. Phillips [Henry Phillips], Dec. 13, 1885; 9x5-1/2; Allen, Harrison, 1841-1897
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p.,end. Asking for favor in connection with loan of publication from the Society.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Dec. 13, 1885; 3x5; Eliot, Charles William, 1834-1926
    Cambridge, [Mass.], L.on postal card S.in another hand. 1p., end.,and add. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to librarian of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], December 14, 1885; 9-1/2x5-1/2; G. & B. Westermann Brothers
    New York, L. 1p.,end. Mutilated. Order for publication.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Dec. 14, 1885; 8x5; U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey
    Phila., A.L.S.:Spencer C.McCorkle. 1p. Answers question about charts.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Dec. 15, 1885; 8x5; Geological Society of Glasgow
    A.L.S.:James White,librarian. 2p.,end. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S. [Henry Phillips], Dec. 15, 1885; 8x5; Michael, Helen Abbott, 1857-1904
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p.,end. Concerning her article for the proceedings.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Dec. 16, 1885; 9x5-1/2; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    A.L.S. 1p.,end. Asking for loan of publication. On same sheet is letter from [Persifor] Frazer to [Henry] Phillips, Dec.16, 1885.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Dec. 16, 1885; 9x5-1/2; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    A.L.S. 1p.,end. Concerning loan of publications. Refers to [J.P.] Lesley. On same sheet as letter from [Persifor] Frazer to [Henry] Phillips, Dec.16, 1885.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Dec. 17, 1885; 10x8; Philadelphia. Post office
    Phila., T.L.S.: W[illia]m F. Harrity,postmaster. 1p. Enc.wanting. Thanks for calling attention to error.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Dec. 17, 1885; 3x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add.,end. Asking for announcement of some remarks he will make on the physical conditions of memory.
  - Letter to librarian of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Dec. 19, 1885; 8-1/2x6; E. Steiger & Co.
    New York, L. 1p.and add.,end. Order for publication.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Dec. 21, 1885; 8x5; U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey
    Phila., A.L.S.:Spencer C.McCorkle. 1p.,end. Enc.wanting. Sends charts.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Dec. 22, 1885; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 2P.and end. Concerning obituary of [H.] Hagert. Concerning Society business. Refers to [J.S.] Price,and [P] Wetherill.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Dec. 22, 1885; 6-1/2x4-1/2; Allen, Harrison, 1841-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Agrees to prepare obituary of A.Smith.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Dec. 22, 1885; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Trübner & Co.
    [London], L.on postal card. 1p.and add.,end. Concerning publications.
  - Memorandum, Dec. 22, 1885; 5x8; Redfield, John Howard, 1815-1895
    A.D.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Concerning a copy made of the Michaux journal. Asa Gray, [C.S.] Sargent and the APS are mentioned.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 23, 1885; 3x5; Cohen, Charles J. (Charles Joseph), 1847-1927
    Phila., L.on postal card. 1p.and add. Does not deal in ballot-boxes.
  - Letter to W[illiam] F.Harrity,postmaster, Phila., Dec. 23, 1885; 10x8; Madara, William B.
    Phila., L.S. 2p. Concerning error in delivery of APS mail. Refers to H.Phillips. Enclosed originally in letter from Philadelphia post office to [H.] Phillips, Dec.24, 1885.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Dec. 23, 1885; 3x5; Schwarz, G. A., co.
    Phila., L.on postal card. 1p.and add. Does not keep ballot-boxes.
  - Letter to the secretary of A.P.S. [Henry Phillips], Dec. 23, 1885; University of Oxford.
  - Letter to J.P. Lesley, Dec. 24, 1885; 5x7-1/2; Columbia University
    A.L.S.:George H[all] Baker,librarian. 2p.,end. Order for publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Dec. 24, 1885; 5x4; Lagen, Charles Augustus, 1849-1916
    A.L.S. 2p. Concerning [H.S.] Hagert.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Dec. 24, 1885; 8x3-1/2; Philadelphia. Post office
    Phila., L.S.:W[illia]m F. Harrity,postmaster. 1p. Enc.wanting. Refers him to enclosed report. For enclosure, see letter from W.B. Madara to W.F. Harrity, Dec.23, 1885.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 28, 1885; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Kongelige Nordiske oldskriftselskab (Denmark)
    Copenhagen, A.L.on postal card S.:Sophus Müller. 1p.,end.,and add. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Dec. 29, 1885; 8x5; Mayer, Alfred M. (Alfred Marshall), 1836-1897
    Hoboken, N.J., L.S. 1p. Concerning the bust of [A.] Lavoisier which was found in the Society's loft. Refers to [G.] Barker.
  - Note to [Henry] Phillips, Dec. 30, 1885; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    A.N.S. 1p.end. Asking him to send [F.A.] Genth the paper he wants. On same sheet as letter from Genth to Brinton, Dec.30, 1885.
  - Letter to D[aniel] G.Brinton, Dec. 30, 1885; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Genth, F. A. (Frederick Augustus), 1820-1893
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Asking to have [H.] Abbott's paper sent to him. On same sheet is note from Brinton to Phillips, [Dec.30, 1885].
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Dec. 31, 1885; 9x5-1/2; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p.,end. Asking for extra copies of his papers. Refers to [D.] Brinton.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Dec. 31, 1885; 3x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerning appointment with him.
  - Memorandum pertaining to the cancellation of 105 lines in [E.D.] Cope's paper on the Extinct mammalia of the valley of Mexico, 1885; 5x9-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    D. 1p., end.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, [1885?]; 7-1/2x4-1/2; Cambridge Philosophical Society
    Cambridge, [Eng.], Printed L.filled in in ms.S.:R[ichard] T[etley] Glazebrook,secretary. 1p. Thanks for publication.
  - List of Charts, [1885?]; 10x8; U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey
    Phila., D. 1p. Listed are twenty-nine charts.
  - Memorandum of several extracts taken from APS Minutes, [1885]; 8x5; American Philosophical Society
    D.in the hand of Henry Phillips. 1p. Ballooning experiments. Mentioned is B.Franklin, among others.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 2, 1886; 8x5; Schele de Vere, M. (Maximilian), 1820-1898
    University of Virginia, A.L.S.in 3rd.P. 1p. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 2, 1886; 8x5; Gerard, W. R.
    New York, A.L.S. 1p.,end. Asking for article on Passamaquoddy tongue.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 2, 1886; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Buffalo Public Library (Buffalo, N.Y.)
    Buffalo, A.L.S.:J[oseph] N[elson] Larned. 1p., end. Order for publication.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S. [Henry Phillips], Jan. 4, 1886; 8x5; Peters, C. H. F. (Christian Heinrich Friedrich), 1813-1890
    Clinton, New York, A.L.S. 1p.,end. Enc.wanting. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 4, 1886; 10x8; Frieze, Henry S. (Henry Simmons), 1817-1889
    Ann Arbor, Mich., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Offers his publications to the Society.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Sergeant Price, Jan. 4, 1886; 8x5-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    Phila., A.L.S.:H[enry] Phillips. 1p.,end. Concerning purchase of a typewriter for the Society. On same sheet is letter from J.Sergeant Price to [Henry Phillips], Jan.5, 1886.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 4, 1886; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Davenport Academy of Natural Sciences
    Davenport, Iowa, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.;W.H.Pratt. 1p., end. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 5, 1886; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Buffalo Public Library (Buffalo, N.Y.)
    Buffalo, A.L.S. J[oseph] N[elson] Larned. 1p., end. Asking question about Society's publication.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Jan. 5, 1886; 9-1/2x8; Hunking, A. W.
    Lowell, Mass., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Asking for map of Massachusetts.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips;], Jan. 5, 1886; 8x5-1/2; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    A.L.S.with initials. 1p.and add.,end. Concerning purchase of a typewriter for the Society. On same sheet as letter from APS to J.Sergeant Price, Jan.4, 1886.
  - Letter to Henry Phillip, Jan. 6, 1886; 8x5; Gatschet, Albert S. (Albert Samuel), 1832-1907
    Wash., D.C., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Concerning articles for the Proceedings.
  - Letter to Henry C[harles] Lea, Jan. 6, 1886; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Trübner, Karl J.
    Strassburg, L.on postal card. 1p.and add.,end. Order for APS publication.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Jan. 7, 1886; 9x5-12; Engineers Club of Philadelphia
    Phila., Printed L.filled in in ms.S.:Howard Murphy,secretary. 1p. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to librarian of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Jan. 8, 1886; 3x5; Genth, F. A. (Frederick Augustus), 1820-1893
    [Phila.], L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Acknowledges receipt of H.Abbott's paper.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 8, 1886; 8x5; Houston, Edwin J. (Edwin James), 1847-1914
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Acknowledges receipt of letter.
  - Letter to Henry M.[sic] Phillips, Jan. 11, 1886; 3x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.,end.,and add. Concerning printing matters.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 12, 1886; 8x5; Houston, Edwin J. (Edwin James), 1847-1914
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Request for paper.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Jan. 12, 1886; 3x5; Lesley, J. P. (J. Peter), 1819-1903
    [Phila.], A.L.on postal card S.in 3rd.P. 1p.and add.,end. Asking that an announcement be made of his remarks on the Hebrew word Shaddai.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 12, 1886; 8-1/2x5-1/2; M’Calla & Stavely
    L.in 3rd P. 1p.,end.,and add. Printing matter.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Jan. 13, 1886; 3x5; Wiegand, Thomas S., 1825-1909
    Phila., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.,end.,and add. Concerning publication.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 13, 1886; 10x8; Frieze, Henry S. (Henry Simmons), 1817-1889
    Ann Arbor, A.L.S. 1p.,end. Discusses his work on Virgil.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Jan. 13, 1886; 8x5; Royal Statistical Society (Great Britain)
    London, A.L.S.:J[oseph] Whittall,secretary. 2p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to H.M.Phillips[Henry Phillips], Jan. 13, 1886; 3x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add.,end. Printing matter.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Jan. 14, 1886; 3x5; Wiegand, Thomas S., 1825-1909
    [Phila.], A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Apologizes for his error.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 14, 1886; 9x5-1/2; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p.and end. Gives estimated cost of maps to accompany his paper.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Jan. 15, 1886; 9x5-1/2; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p.,end. Asking for return of his manuscript.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 16, 1886; 8x5; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Concerning [J.A.] Houdon.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Jan. 16, 1886; 5x8; A. Dulau & Co.
    London, L. 2p.,end. Enc.wanting. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 16, 1886; 10x8; Gatschet, Albert S. (Albert Samuel), 1832-1907
    Wash.,D.C., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Acknowledges receipt of his diploma of membership in the Society.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Jan. 16, 1886; 8x5; Hale, Horatio, 1817-1896
    Clinton, Canada, A.L.S. 4p.,end. Concerning his work on the Wlastukweek Indians. Refers to J.C.Pilling.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 16, 1886; 10x8; Philadelphia. Post office
    Phila., T.L.S.:W[illia]m F. Harrity,postmaster. 1p.,end. Answering his complaint about delayed deliveries of postal cards. Refers to J. Solis Cohen.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Jan. 18, 1886; 10x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Wash.,D.C., L.S.:S[pencer] F[ullerton] Baird. 1p. Enc.wanting. Concerning a package from [A.] Packard.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 18, 1886; 10-1/2x8; Lesley, J. P. (J. Peter), 1819-1903
    [Phila.], L.S.in another hand. 1p.,end. Concerning the way certain Society matters were dealt with while he was librarian.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Jan. 18, 1886; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Peary, Robert E. (Robert Edwin), 1856-1920
    Wash.,D.C., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Asking for article on Greenland.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 18, 1886; 8x5; Green, Traill, 1813-1897
    Easton, Pa., A.L.S.in 3rd.P. 1p.,end. Enc.wanting. Offers Society a new photograph of himself.
  - Letter to president of A.P.S.[Frederick Fraley], Jan. 18, 1886; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Pector, Désiré
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. Asking about conditions of membership in the Society. Refers to D.G.Brinton, among others.
  - Letter to librarian of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Jan. 19, 1886; 9x5-1/2; State Historical Society of Wisconsin
    Madison, A.L.S.:Dan[iel] S[teele] Durrie,librarian. 1p.,end. Calls attention to mispaging in the Proceedings.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Jan. 19, 1886; 8-1/2x5-1/2; France. Ministère de l'agriculture, du commerce et des travaux publics
    Paris, L.S.:[Charles] R[enè] Zeiller. 1p.,end. In French. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 20, 1886; 9x6; MacAlister, James, 1840-1913
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for sending the documents.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 23, 1886; 10x8; Geological Survey (U.S.)
    Wash.,D.C., Printed L.filled in in ms.S.:James C. Pilling, chief clerk. 2p. Order for publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 23, 1886; 5x3; Gatschet, Albert S. (Albert Samuel), 1832-1907
    Wash.,D.C., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Order for publication.